Helen Anderson

Personal Information

Address:

4/45 Hampton Circuit, Yarralumla ACT 2600

Phone:

0450 010 325

Email:

Helen.G.Anderson@me.com

LinkedIn:

http://au.linkedin.com/in/handerson1

GitHub:

https://github.com/grace-anderson

Citizenship:

Australian Citizen, New Zealand Citizen

Security Clearance:

Negative Vetting 1 (NV1) (Australia)

Summary

Over 15 years' experience as a functional business analyst in wide range of domains (airline, university, federal government) augmented with programming and technical skills. Newly honed skills in JavaScript, React, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB from a full stack bootcamp with interest in design thinking and UX. Advanced knowledge of BPMN with OMG certification. Excellent communication and negotiation skills with demonstrated ability in business requirements capture and analysis, process modelling, through to requirements testing. Able to successfully engage directly with business areas to understand requirements and translate these into technically achievable deliverables.

Certified Business Analysis Professional (CBAP). Certified Expert in BPMN 2 (OMG). Prince2 Practitioner.

Earning a certificate in Full Stack Web Development with

the University of Sydney.

Business Analyst Competencies

An expert level business analysis practitioner who

- drives insight to complex situations
- addresses any challenge or opportunity, regardless of level of complexity,
- takes initiative to find and deliver business value
- guides others to help them deliver better business outcomes,
- is sought after for expertise and guidance
- thrives when collaborating as a team to deliver solutions

Focus areas of expertise

- planning and facilitating stakeholder engagement
- requirements discovery, elicitation, analysis, documentation, validation (waterfall and agile contexts)
- process modelling and analysis, business process improvement
- troubleshooting and problem solving
- collaborative enabling and delivery throughout software development lifecycle from discovery, requirements elicitation, design, through to testing, UAT, implementation and maintenance

Technical skills

JavaScript ES6+, React, CSS3, Bootstrap CSS, HTML5, Express, Node, mySQL, sequelize ORM, NoSQL (MongoDB), mongoose, Heroku, Handlebars

Developer Portfolio: https://github.com/grace-anderson/react-portfolio

Recent experience

Senior Manager: Business Analyst

Synergy Group (March 2021 to present), Canberra ACT

- Business Process Analysis and Improvement: Australian Communications and Media Authority (ACMA) (Current engagement)
- Service Experience Team, GovERP, Services Australia (March-May 2022)
- Department of Defence: Elicit and model business process requirements preliminary to ERP implementation (Modelpedia) (July 2021-Feb 2022)
- CIO Group, Department of Defence: Design and deliver Innovation Operating Model and Innovation User Guide (April June 2021)

Management Consultant: Business Analyst

Apis (part of Accenture) (2018-2021), Canberra ACT

- 2IC to Business Design Team Leader
- Department of Health: Develop system requirements for policy proposals (NPPs) in response to Royal Commission into Aged Care Quality and Safety
- Department of Health: Multiple projects implementing enhancements to My Aged Care CRM system (.net, Siebel)

Business Specialist – Student Administration

Charles Darwin University (2011-2018), Darwin NT

- Lead Business Analyst on multiple projects enhancing student management system in collaboration with business users and vendor (Oracle, Callista (now Tribal), Jira and Confluence)
- Lead Business Analyst delivering successful implementation of Curriculum Design and Approval Module (Callista (now Tribal))

Business System Analyst - PeopleSoft, Enterprise Systems

Air New Zealand (2007-2011), Auckland NZ

- Lead analysis utilising Green Belt Six Sigma Lean principles on a critical business improvement project, significantly improving the payroll close process. Business gains were to remove staff overtime requirements and gain measurable improvement in teams' morale.
- Planning and implementing system upgrades, in coordination with vendors, contractors, and in-house technical teams, prompt resolution of urgent issues, managing stakeholder expectations
- Rules writing simple changes to payroll rules
- System testing complex payroll rules and HR system development

Recent development project

Book Nest

Code: https://github.com/grace-anderson/book-nest

Deployed app: https://the-book-nest.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Book Nest was designed following the MVC (Model View Control) design pattern using a MySQL database with Sequelize ORM, an Express is back end, and Handlebars templating to present data to the user.
- Role: Product Owner and Development Team Member
- Tools: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Node, Express, Handlebars, Express-Session, MySQL2, Sequelize, dotenv, bcrypt

Qualifications and certifications

2022	Certificate, Full Stack Web Development (University of Sydney) (in progress)
2022	OMG-Certified Expert in BPMN 2 - Fundamental (Business Process Management)
2021	Cert IV in Programming (Canberra Institute of Technology) (in progress)
2020	PRINCE2 Practitioner
2019	Certificate IV in Training and Assessment (Canberra Institute of Technology)
2017	CBAP (Certified Business Analysis Professional, IIBA, BABOK v.3)
2010	Postgraduate Diploma in Business (Information Systems), (University of Auckland, Graduate School of Enterprise)
2003	Bachelor of Business (Major Management), First Class Honours, (Auckland University of Technology)